README.md 2024-07-30



Social Media: GitHub | LinkedIn

A passionate developer with over 8 years' experience in front end development with extensive knowledge of JavaScript/TypeScript using frameworks such as Vue.js and React.js. Skilled at write clean and concise code that is easy to maintain.

Currently I am working on a personal project to index and categories rap battles. It's a full stack application using the Next.js framework with social login. I have built out the admin section for a user to manage artists, leagues and battles hosted on YouTube. The data is then presented to logged out user and made searchable using Algolia search.

Education 🎓

Makers Academy (July 2016 to September 2016)

- Curiosity and a hungry passion for code
- Independent learner and problem-solver
- OOP, TDD, SOLID, MVC
- Software Craftsmanship
- Ruby, Rails, Javascript
- Rspec, Jasmine, Mocha, Zombie

MidKent College Medway (2005 to 2006)

• IT Practitioners BTEC

Experience

Freelance (November 2023 to Present) Front End Developer

Working with various clients to build and maintain their web apps using React.js and Vue.js. I focus on creating responsive, dynamic user interfaces and making sure everything runs smoothly.

- Figma designs to React/Vue apps
- · General bug fixes and code refactoring
- Implementing features such as language translation

Hectare (August 2022 to November 2023) Senior Front End Developer

Development of a marketplace and inventory web application for the farming industry using the Nuxt.js framework for the offline capabilities when entering data out in the field.

- Working with the design team and planning out features
- Building reuseable interactive UI components
- Upgrading components from Vue options api to Vue composition api
- Vue component testing with Jest and Cypress for higher test coverage
- Migrating the codebase from JavaScript to TypeScript for maintainability

README.md 2024-07-30

LineTen (March 2021 to August 2022) Senior Front End Developer

Building out dashboards to manage and track drivers and deliveries in real time using Vue.js.

- Mentoring and pair programming with junior developers
- Upgrading components from Vue options api to Vue composition api
- Development of a component library for brand consistency across all web applications
- Developed a starter repo for frontend and backend code with easy deployment using Docker

Croud (August 2019 to February 2021) Front End Developer

Planning and development of green field projects to manage outsourced marketing tasks and provide website analysis and feedback.

- Development of multiple dashboards with the Nuxt.js framework with server side rendered pages
- · Building custom chart components using Chart.js to display additional data
- Upgrading the codebase with TypeScript for easier debugging

Mettrr (August 2017 to July 2019) Front End Developer

Development of small business websites using a independently-hosted static site generator and a JSON configuration with hundreds of pre built HTML templates.

- Developement of a custom static site generator built using JavaScript
- Managing AWS lambda function which host the static site generator code and only runs when generating a website
- Converting website template designs into HTML and CSS
- Development of a Vue.js promotional website and dashboard

Finimize (March 2017 to July 2017) Front End Developer Internship

Development of a finanical news web application components using JavaScript and React.js.

- Development of simple React.js components
- · Component unit testing using Jest
- Redesigning and creating new web pages
- · Converting website design into a WordPress theme
- Managing and creating email marketing templates using Mailchimp

Freelance (2016 to 2017) Front End Developer

- Convert website designs into HTML & CSS
- WordPress theme development
- Landing pages connected to MailChimp API

Benson & Company (2014 to 2016) Front End Developer

- Design and build any new websites.
- Ensure all company websites where up to date and running efficiently.
- Format schedule blog posts to be released every Monday.
- Design and schedule all newsletters using MailChimp.

README.md 2024-07-30

Various (2007 to 2014) Such as: cashier, restaurants and bars